IHSAN SALEHEEN

Virtual Assistant

Dhaka, Bangladesh | <u>ihsan.saleheen@gmail.com</u>

Profile, Portfolio & Website

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ihsansaleheen/
- https://www.youtube.com/@excelfix
- https://github.com/Ihsansaleheen?tab=repositories
- https://ihsansaleheen.blogspot.com/

Professional Summary

Detail oriented virtual assistant professional with **5 years** of experience. Created financial models & presentations on different purpose, extract findings from documents to ensure informed decision making. Managed multiple stakeholders on transfer of ownership. Working as a content creator on **MS-Excel, google workspace & different office management tools** in YouTube.

Work Experience

Brain Station 23 Ltd | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Accountant & Audit Executive | 10/2019 - 2/2021

- Conducted market research on more than 2000 IT company's salary structure & concluded that
 IT companies in Bangladesh spends more than 80% of their revenue on employee's salary &
 compensation which contributed to revise my employer's own salary structure.
- Worked in ESOP (Employee Stock Option Plan) financial modelling, made company's cumulative profitability report (CPR) in a more convenient manner, studied annual reports, books, web & other sources to get insight as instructed by the CEO.
- Worked as an intermediary to transfer 8.70% of the company's ownership.

National Credit Ratings Ltd – Dhaka, Bangladesh

Junior Financial Analyst | 09/2018 - 2/2019

- Conducted credit rating of **82** companies on an average of **1 company** per day.
- Maintained relationship with bankers & clients on an average of 3 times per company.

Green Delta Securities Ltd – Dhaka, Bangladesh

Assistant Manager | 01/2015 - 05/2015

- Prepared research reports on sector and companies of the capital market
- Maintained bank reconciliation statements and executed payments to clients daily

Internship

After BBA@ BDBL (Understanding the general banking operation & done feasibility reports)

Education

• BBA in Accounting & Information Systems | University of Dhaka | 3.14 out of 4.00

Accomplishments

- Recipient of Dutch Bangla Bank Merit Scholarship for 4 years in the graduation level.
- Passed 7th NTRCA teachers registration examination.

Hobbies & Interest

- Technology (Explore different AI tools & stock screening websites)
- Investment (Micro Investor in Dhaka Stock Exchange for 10 years. Traded in XM.com)

Membership

- Life time member of Bangladesh Red Crescent Society
- Life time member of Quantum Foundation Bangladesh

Certifications

- Data Analyst in Power Bi | Data Camp | 51 Hours
- Power BI Data Analytics for All Levels | Codebasics.io | 17.40 hours
- Excellence with Excel | Bohubrihi.com | 40 hours
- Excel: Mother of Business Intelligence | Codebasics.io | 09 hours
- Ultimate SQL Bootcamp | MSB Academy | 14 hours
- SQL Beginner to Advance for data Professionals | Codebasics.io | 11 hours
- Data Analysis | Study Mart | 4 months
- Financial Modeling Master Class | Professional Finance Studies | 4 days
- Financial analysis, planning & budgeting | Udemy.com | 23 hours
- Value investing & Investment Banking | Udemy.com | 20 hours
- Microsoft Office Management | Design Tech IT Academy | 3 months
- Graphics Design | Creative IT Ltd | 5 months
- Web Design & Web Development | Creative IT Ltd | 10 months
- Ethical Hacking | E-shikhon | 5 months
- Technical Analysis | TFX Training | 1 month
- Internal Auditing | Bangladesh Institute of Management | Dhaka, 40 hours
- Branding for Competitiveness | Bangladesh Institute of Management, Dhaka | 40 hours
- Virtual Assistant Course | Ghoorilearning.com | 5 hours
- Digital Accounting with QuickBooks | Grameenphone Academy | 8 hours
- Professional Content Writing | Grameenphone Academy | 2.5 hours
- Training on Entrepreneurship | Nijer Bolar Moto Golpo Foundation | 90 days

Technical Skills

- Big Data Analysis | Equity Research | Financial Analysis | Financial Forecasting | Valuation
- Microsoft Power BI | MySQL
- MS Excel (I have a YouTube channel on Excel: https://www.youtube.com/@excelfix)
- Trello | Google Workspace
- MS Word | MS Power Point | HTML | CSS

Soft Skills

- Good Communication & Teamwork (Have teaching experience of Accounting & Finance. Also worked as Course Coordinator of Spoken & Written English in a Language Training Center)
- Quick & Consistent learner (Make content on my YouTube channels on MS Excel, different AI & office management tools, Prompt Engineering, Google Dorking etc.)

Language Skills

• English (Advance), Hindi (Working knowledge), Bengali (Native)

References

- Md. Nazim Uddin Bhuiyan | Professor | Department of AIS, University of Dhaka |
 +880 01818946368 | nazim_bhuiyan@yahoo.com | Relationship: Academic
- Raisul Kabir | Managing director & CEO | Brain Station 23 Ltd | +880 1713458492 | raisulk@gmail.com | Relationship: Professional

Declaration

"I CERTIFY THAT ALL INFORMATION STATED IN THIS RESUME IS TRUE AND COMPLETE, I AUTHORIZE THE RECEIVER OF THIS RESUME TO VERIFY THE INFORMATION PROVIDED IN THIS RESUME"